Yunxiang Zhang

370 Jay St, Brooklyn, NY 11201, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are at the intersection of virtual/augmented reality, human-computer interaction, and computational photography/imaging. I enjoy combining theoretical insights from physical, biological, and cognitive sciences with machine learning tools to solve challenging real-world problems.

EDUCATION

New York University Brooklyn, NY 11201, USA

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2022 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Oi Sun

The Chinese University of Hong Kong Hong Kong SAR, China Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

Master of Philosophy in Information Engineering

Thesis: Towards Physically Realistic Human-Environment Interaction in Virtual and Augmented Reality

Advisor: Prof. Dahua Lin

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Shanghai, China

Sep 2017 - Mar 2020 Master of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Thesis: Similarity-Based Approach to Neural Network Pruning

Advisor: Prof. Bingbing Ni

École Polytechnique Palaiseau 91128, France

Diplôme d'Ingénieur in Computer Science (double-degree program between SJTU and EP)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Shanghai, China

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

Sep 2013 - Aug 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Research Intern, Vector Institute Toronto, ON M5G 1M1, Canada

Supervisor: Prof. Nicolas Papernot Mar 2020 - Jun 2020

Research Intern, LTCI Télécom Paris Paris 75013, France

Supervisor: Prof. Samy Blusseau, Prof. Santiago Velasco-Forero, Prof. Isabelle Bloch, and Prof. Jesús Angulo Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

Software Development Intern, SNCF Saint Denis 93200, France

Supervisor: Loïc Hamelin Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

PUBLICATIONS

- Modeling and Optimizing Neck Muscle Comfort in VR/AR. Yunxiang Zhang, Kenneth Chen, Qi Sun. Under review 2023
- Force-Aware Interface via Electromyography for Natural VR/AR Interaction. Yunxiang Zhang, Benjamin Liang, Boyuan Chen, Paul M. Torrens, S. Farokh Atashzar, Dahua Lin, Qi Sun. ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia 2022) Paper
- CaPC Learning: Confidential and Private Collaborative Learning. Christopher A. Choquette-Choo*, Natalie Dullerud*, Adam Dziedzic*, Yunxiang Zhang*, Somesh Jha, Nicolas Papernot, Xiao Wang. International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021) Paper
- Exploiting Channel Similarity for Network Pruning. Chenglong Zhao, Yunxiang Zhang, Bingbing Ni. IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology 2023 Paper
- Max-plus Operators Applied to Filter Selection and Model Pruning in Neural Networks. Yunxiang Zhang, Samy Blusseau, Santiago Velasco-Forero, Isabelle Bloch, Jesus Angulo. International Symposium on Mathematical Morphology and Its Application to Signal and Image Processing (ISMM 2019) Paper
 - * Equal contributions, authors ordered alphabetically.

AWARDS

New York University SoE Fellowship (2022 – 2023)

The Chinese University of Hong Kong Postgraduate Scholarship (2020 - 2022)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University SPEIT Academic Excellence Scholarship (2015 – 2016)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Ardian Scholarship (2014 - 2015)

Professional Services

Reviewer for AAAI 2021, IEEE ISMAR 2022, IEEE VR 2023

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, Virtual and Augmented Reality (CS-GY 9223), New York University2022 FallTeaching Assistant, Final Year Project (IERG 4998/4999), The Chinese University of Hong Kong2020 – 2022

SKILLS

- Programming: C/C++, Python, C#, Java, CUDA, Matlab
- Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Libigl, Eigen, Git, CMake, OpenMP
- Software: Blender, Unity, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, Matlab, Mathematica, MeshLab
- Language: Mandarin, English, French